<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Liftingcoder Blog</title>
    <link>https://liftingcoder.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Liftingcoder Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024, Bernhard B.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://liftingcoder.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Laser Cut City Map</title>
      <link>https://liftingcoder.com/laser-cut-city-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liftingcoder.com/laser-cut-city-map/</guid>
      <description>Since I first saw online images of laser-cut city maps, I knew I wanted to build something like that myself. Now, as a proud owner of an Xtool D1 with an Extension Kit for several months, and with my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s birthday just around the corner and no gift yet in hand, I realized this would be the perfect opportunity. Choosing the 8th district of Vienna as the motif holds particular significance for my girlfriend, adding a personal touch to the gift.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useless Machine</title>
      <link>https://liftingcoder.com/useless-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 16:03:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liftingcoder.com/useless-machine/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to build my own useless machine. What is a useless machine you ask? It&amp;rsquo;s a simple gadget with a switch that, when flipped on, immediately switches itself off. Sounds like a quirky project, right?&#xA;A Useless Machine in Minecraft&#xA;Even though there are plenty of useless machine designs out there, I wanted mine to differ in these points:&#xA;The device shouldn&amp;rsquo;t drain its battery when not in use.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindful Picture Frame</title>
      <link>https://liftingcoder.com/mindful-picture-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 10:01:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://liftingcoder.com/mindful-picture-frame/</guid>
      <description>Who knows this problem? Over the years, one has accumulated gigabytes of photos, capturing a snapshot of every moment worth remembering, only to hardly ever look at the photos again. That&amp;rsquo;s how it was for me too - on my Nextcloud Share, there are tens of thousands of photos, neatly organized and sorted, condemned to gather digital dust.&#xA;But I wanted to change that. And thus, the Mindful Picture Frame was born.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
